Nicole: So why is it important to manage
and promote a positive digital identity?
Most people today have an
online digital identity.
It is therefore important to
carefully manage and maintain it
professionally and keep it up to date.
Abraham: It is always essential as a cyber
security professional to promote your
digital identity in a positive light.
So, what exactly does a
digital identity consist of?
Nicole: Everything you do on the
internet be it publishing your own
social media posts, blogs or websites,
contributes to your digital footprint,
this also includes wherever your name
is mentioned when it is ‘Googled’.
Abraham: When setting up your social
media channels, you should always
try to think about how you show
yourself by the name you use and
the photographs that identify you.
This can help to establish
your personal brand.
Remember that any online content
out there will be accessible to
others for an indefinite period!
Nicole: It’s also good to think
about any comment you make and
how you engage with others.
Don’t say anything online that you
wouldn’t say in public and don’t show
any photos that you wouldn’t be happy
for your potential employer to see!
Abraham: Try and show yourself in
a professional light by setting
up a professional profile on
sites like LinkedIn and Twitter.
You can also use these platforms
to follow appropriate companies and
look for recruitment opportunities
and potential employers.
Nicole: Showcase the best version
of yourself and make professional
comments on current cyber security
issues and posts that relate to your
hobbies to enhance your employability.
Abraham: Create bios that
reflect your skills and are
appropriate to potential roles.
Nicole: As a cyber security professional,
your digital identity, should really
stand out as positive and professional
and show that you have nothing to hide!
Abraham: Therefore, it is important
to always think carefully about
everything that you post or comment on.
And remember that if you can find
your details out there then so can any
third parties and potential employers.